# **Guille Lopez**

## Engineer at eBay

guille@ductil.org

## Summary

I never thought I will become a programmer, but just before starting college Internet appeared out of blue and since then I have been fascinated with it. So being a developer has been for me the natural tool for approaching this fascination, and that's what I've been doing on the last 10 years. First working on digital advertisement for production companies in Barcelona and New York for some big clients, such as Google, Barclays or Mitsubishi. And in recent times, and driven for a motivation coming from side projects, on the startup world, helping to build the social shopping site Sypply.

## **Specialties**

Internet.

I create sites, apps, ebooks, blogs, commerce sites, CMS, mobile sites, iphone apps and many other things coding mainly on HTML, Javascript, CSS, XML, Ruby on Rails, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, ActionScript and a little bit of Objective-C, also using platforms such as jQuery, WordPress, Open Graph, Facebook Connect, Google Analytics, Google Checkout and any other one the project could need.

## Experience

### Front-end Engineer at Sypply

September 2011 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Svpply is a New York company of designers and engineers with a good notion of how to build a new kind of retail platform.

#### Lead Developer at B-Reel

2009 - September 2011 (2 years)

Taking care of concepting, prototyping and developing projects for big brands such as: Google, Barclays or Mitsubishi.

#### Interactive Developer at B-Reel

April 2009 - October 2009 (7 months)

#### Independent programmer at ductil.org

August 2008 - April 2009 (9 months)

Working for Aer Studio, Wladimir Marnich, Marti Guixe, Hector Serrano, Double You, Anna Sodupe, Ferran Izquierdo and other clients.

### Professor at Elisava

February 2009 - February 2009 (1 month)

Teaching a three-day workshop about Flash and WordPress at the Master in Design and Architecture.

### Senior interactive programmer at Xnografics

March 2008 - August 2008 (6 months)

Working for clients like: Zara, Malibu or Silenci.

### Interactive Programmer at DoubleYou

May 2006 - March 2008 (1 year 11 months)

Working for clients like: Nike, Audi, Cacique, Aquarius or San Miguel.

#### **Interactive Programmer at CP Proximity**

December 2005 - May 2006 (6 months)

Working for clients like: Audi or Estrella Damm.

2 recommendations available upon request

## Education

#### **Universitat Ramon Llull**

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Multimedia Engineering, 1999 - 2004

#### **ESDI**

Electronic Art & Digital Design, 2002 - 2003

# **Guille Lopez**

Engineer at eBay

guille@ductil.org



# 2 people have recommended Guille

"sólo hablaré en presencia de mi abogado"

— Nacho Rapallo, Owner, yestoall, managed Guille at CP Proximity

"Guille is one of the best flash programmers that I know. Different from others, he is really interest in interactive and always worried with the final experience of the consumer. Work with him was nice to see how almost everything can be done, with more or less work."

— Marcio Ismail, Art Director, CP Proximity, worked directly with Guille at CP Proximity

Contact Guille on LinkedIn